Ruth Krauss Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
- Series VIII: Poetry, undated, 1958-1988
  - "Westport Insurrection" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1650)
  - "What Am I a Mouse or a Volcano" [tss and copy], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1651)
  - When I Walk I Change the Earth
    - "Poem In Progress" [notes], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1652)
    - "Changes" (early version of book), undated (Box 54:, Folder 1653)
    - "End Song" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1654)
    - "When I Walk I Change the Earth" section [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1655)
    - "Changes" (early version of "When I Walk.. .") [tss and copies], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1656)
    - "When I Walk I Change the Earth" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1657)
    - ["The world is different when it breaks"] [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1658)
    - "Changes" (early version) [paste-ups and copies], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1659)
      Fragile!
    - "A Semi-Annual Checklist of Poetry" [brochure], 1979 (Box 54:, Folder 1660)
  - Signed page, 1978 (Box 55:, Folder 1687)
  - "Where" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1661)
  - "Where Are the Snows of Yesteryear" [mss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1662)
  - "While My Hair Was Still" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1663)
  - "While My Hair Was Still" [annotated tss], 1961 November 27 (Box 54:, Folder 1664)
  - "While My Hair Was Still" [mss], 1961 December (Box 54:, Folder 1665)
  - "While My Hair Was Still" [mss], 1962 February (Box 54:, Folder 1666)
  - "White, Black, and Blue" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1667)
  - "Wild Angel Poem" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1668)
  - "Wild Rice Refrain" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1669)
  - "Wild Shines"/"First Day of the New.. ." [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1670)
  - "The Wild Stairs of Manhattan in a Girl by the Sea" [tss and copies; See also Somebody Else's Nut Tree, Series II.], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1671)
  - "Winnie Plus Early Japanese Writers and Eeyore" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1672)
  - "With the Collaboration of a Husband" [tss and copy], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1673)
  - "Word" poems [tss, mss, copies], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1674)
  - "Word Song" [copy], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1675)
  - "Word, Where Are You Going?" [tss, mss, copies], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1676)
  - "Words" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1677)
  - "World" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1678)
  - "Worlds of the Word, Unite" [copy], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1679)
  - "Worn-Out Word: World" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1680)
  - "Worst Poems of the Year" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1681)
  - "Yes I Said Yes I Will Yes" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1682)
  - Young Collection (unpublished) [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1683)
  - "The Young Words" [copies], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1684)
- Series IX: Artifacts, undated, 1929-1992
  - "Gutenberg's Invention" by Friedrich and Bertha Goudy [print], 1929 (Box 55:, Folder 1694)
  - Jimmy Ernst Art Show [signed poster], 1973 (Box 55:, Folder 1696)
  - "Joseph's Coat" [stationery and drawing], undated (Box 55:, Folder 1691)
  - "Self Portrait after Hieronymus Zosch" [print], 1963 (Box 55:, Folder 1693)
  - "This Is the Age of the Book Mobile" by Remy Charlip [mobile kit], 1970 (Box 55:, Folder 1692)
  - Tillie's Tulips by Robert and Marlene McCracken [teaching aid], 1992 (Box 55:, Folder 1695)
  - Vietnam Protest materials, undated (Box OS:, Folder 858)
- Series X: Photographs, undated, 1962-1982
  - Ruth Leona and Ruth Krauss with Miguel's drawing, 26 Dock Rd., [b&w print], 1962 (Box 56:, Folder 1697)
  - Robert L. Peters, Berlin, [col. Print], 1968 Summer (Box 56:, Folder 1698)
  - Glezer Gallery opening of Crockett Johnson's Schematic paintings show, [b&w prints and 4"x5" neg.], [1970s] (Box 56:, Folder 1699)
  - Ruth Krauss, [col. prints and 35mm negs.], 1970 March (Box 56:, Folder 1700)
  - Freya Littledale, Inner Harbor, Baltimore, Maryland, [col. prints], [1980s] (Box 56:, Folder 1701)
  - Ruth Krauss, [col. print], 1982 June (Box 56:, Folder 1702)
  - Crockett Johnson, [b&w prints and 35mm neg.], undated (Box 56:, Folder 1703)
  - Ruth Krauss and Crockett Johnson, Photographer: Lillian Tonnaire-Taylor [contact sheet and b&w 35mm negs.], undated (Box 56:, Folder 1704)
  - Travel postcards, [col. and b&w], undated (Box 56:, Folder 1705)
  - Unidentified photographs [col. polaroid and b&w print], undated (Box 56:, Folder 1706)